<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="Letters.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <letter n="1">
      <pen type="handwrit">Left <place name="Loen">Loen</place> for <place name="Bal">Balestrand</place> <date when="1955-08-22">Aug 22</date></pen>
      <l n="1"/>Departed from <place where="Loen">Loen</place> about 9. With a picnic. Went <corr type="miss text" aka="east">Ea_t</corr>for
        <l n="2"/>a few miles - Toward the glacier where we were yesterday.
        <l n="3"/>Then north and east around the end of the Nord Fjord
        <l n="4"/>passing little clusters ofhouses. Edges of bright orange
        <l n="5"/>seaweed along the edges of the water. The water is a bit
        <l n="6"/>salt and sea gulls skim about. Even tho it is many
        <l n="7"/>miles from the Sea. Beautiful vista- across the water.
        <l n="8"/>Road winding <corr type="spell err" aka="along">allng</corr> the <corr type="spell err" aka="water's">wates</corr> edge.
     <pen type="doodle">Doodle on left side of page depicting a rough sketch of a house with trees on the roof. It is captioned "Grass on Roof-Tops and Trees".</pen> 
        <l n="9"/>Thro <place name="Utvik">Utvik</place> Went high up thro pine
        <l n="10"/>forrest and then had to turn back- even <corr type="miss text">t</corr>
        <l n="11"/>
            further back then where we <corr type="spell err" aka="photographed">photograped</corr>
      <l n="12"/>the cream colored pony- to the place
        <l n="13"/>at the turn where we photo. the view.
        <l n="14"/>and THERE were my glasses exactly where
        <l n="15"/>I had dropped the from my lap as I got
     <l n="16"/>out ofthe car to take a <corr type="miss text" aka="picture of the">pictu_e ofth</corr>
     <pen type="doodle">Doodle depicting a pair of glasses next to a flower</pen>
      <l n="17"/>lovely view. VERY ,lucky!! Beautiful
        <l n="18"/>ground cover under thepines- heather in big
        <l n="19"/>clumps.)(Steamersdo not come in to <place where="Loen">Loen</place> since
        <l n="20"/>several diasters- great chunks of the <corr type="spell err" aka="mountainsides">mountainzides</corr>
      <l n="21"/>
            sliding down into the fjord and killing
        <l n="22"/>manypeople- there is a tablet on the way
        <l n="23"/>to the glacierto <corr type="spell err" aka="commemorate">commerate</corr> onesuch
        <l n="24"/>happening. <corr type="miss text" aka="Snow">S__ow</corr>
      <corr type="spell err" aka="capped">cappee</corr> mountains.
        <l n="25"/>Stopped at a little village by a rushing frothy river,
        <l n="26"/>and bought some soft drinks from a pretty round faced girl
        <l n="27"/>Again went very high over a mountain range- with grand
        <l n="28"/>views Carpets of fern. Photographed a very WIDE waterfall
        <l n="29"/>At the summit we got out and waited <corr type="spell err" aka="a while">zwhile</corr> until
        <l n="30"/>the spark plugs were cleaned. It was a sort of rest place
     <pen type="doodle">A very rough sketch is located on the right side of the page. It is hard to determine what this doodle is depicting. It might be a car on the summit of the mountain.</pen>
        <l n="31"/>People having coffeein the sun. Some of the
        <l n="32"/>old farms were of intereest- 16 more or less-
        <l n="33"/>buildings in a group Clear reflections in the river.
        <l n="34"/>Like glass and yet it is always moving. Often
        <l n="35"/>great rocks in the river bed where the river
     <l n="36"/>rushes noisily <corr type="spell err" aka="through">thdough</corr>. Brilliant green <corr type="miss text" aka="first i is faded">iin</corr>
        <l n="37"/>the bumpy meadows- like fairy moss. Several cream
        <l n="38"/>colored ponies stopped us in the road- we got
        <l n="39"/>out and fed them biscuts '<corr type="spell err" aka="Lunch">Luch</corr> by the roadside
        <l n="40"/>from the Hotel Alexandra's nice picnic.
        <l n="41"/><corr type="miss text" aka="After">A_ter</corr> an hourwe continued Magnificent
        <l n="42"/>views. Before us the Sojne <corr type="spell err" aka="fjord">fjoyd</corr>
      <l n="43"/>surrounded by snow capped mountains.
     <pen type="doodle">Two horizontal lines with two figures on top of them. The caption reads "Two black kid on wall by the roadside". The figures appear to have four legs, so it is assumed that the "kid"s are baby goats.</pen>
     <pen type="handwrit">arrived <place where="Bal">Balestrand</place></pen>
    </letter>
</root>
