<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
    <letter n="1">
        <penmanship type="Handwriting">Left Loen for Balestrand Aug 22</penmanship>
        Departed from Loen about 9. With a picnic. Went Ea_t (east?) for a few miles - Toward the glacier where we were yesterday. Then north and east around          the end of the Nord Fjord passing little clusters ofhouses. Edges of bright orange seaweed along the edges of the water. The water is a bit (line cuts         off)
        salt and sea gulls skim about. Even tho it is many miles from the Sea. Beautiful vista- across the water.
        <pennmanship type="doodle">(image on side of page)</pennmanship> Road winding allng<corr type="spell err">(along)</corr> the wates<corr type="spell err">(waters)</corr> edge. Thro Utvik Went high up thro pine forrest and then had to turn back-  
    event<corr type="missing text">(cuts off)</corr> further back then where we photograped<corr type="spell err">(photographed)</corr> the cream colored pony- to the place at the turn where we photo. the view. and THERE          were my glasses exactly where I had dropped the from my lap as I got out ofthe car to take a pictu_e ofth<corr type="missing text">(cuts off)</corr> lovely view. VERY ,lucky!!                 Beautiful ground cover under thepines- heather in big clumps.)(Steamersdo not come in to Loen since several diasters- great chunks of the                      mountainzides<corr type="spell err">(mountainsides)</corr> sliding down into the fjord and killing manypeople- there is a tablet on the way to the glacierto commerate<corr type="spell err">(commemorate)</corr> onesuch                 happening. <corr type="">S__ow(snow)</corr> cappee<corr type="spell err">(capped)</corr> mountains. Stopped at a little village by a rushing frothy river, and bought some soft drinks from a pretty              round faced girl Again went very high over a mountain range- with grand views Carpets of fern. Photographed a very WIDE waterfall At the summit we got         out and waited zwhile until the spark plugs were cleaned. It was a sort of rest place People having coffeein the sun. Some of the old farms were of            intereest- 16 more or less- buildings in a group Clear reflections in the river. Like glass and yet it is always moving. Often great rocks in the 
        river bed where teh river rushes noisiluy thdough. Brilliant green iin the bumpy meadows- like fairy moss. Several cream colored ponies stopped us in          the road- we got out and fed them biscuts 'Luch by the roadside from the Hotel Alexandra's nice picnic. A_ter an hourwe continued Magnificent views.           Before us the Sojne fjoyd surrounded by snow capped mountains. <penmanship type="handwriting">Arrived Balestrand.</penmanship>
    </letter>
</root>
